An up-to-date alternative to Opera's standard scrollbars (which should be disabled to avoid double bars. Therefore go to Opera → Settings → Preferences... (Ctrl+F12) → Advanced → Browsing and uncheck "Show scroll bars" )

What's awesome about modern scroll?

+ scrolling is sometimes faster than with Opera's standard bars!
+ its scroll bars don't take up any space so the whole screen width can be used to display what a browser is made for: websites
+ elements or whole pages don't shift by some pixels when content changes and bars become (un)necessary
+ scroll bars are usable in fullscreen mode as well
+ scroll bars automatically hide when they are not needed
+ unique "superbar" which makes it possible to scroll horizontally and vertically at the same time
+ optional buttons for scrolling to the top and bottom of the page
+ behavior and appearance is fully customizable

This extension was originally planned as an update to slim scrollbar by damage92. But since it doesn't have a single line of code in common with the original extension we decided to publish it as a new one. Slim scrollbar will of course continue to exist if you prefer the other implementation or if you are using Opera below 12.10 where modern scroll isn't available. Due to damage92's rare spare time it's not being actively developed at the moment, though.

Changelog:
----------

v 1.X
---------
new: custom scroll function
new: optionally animate scroll to top/bottom
new: read and use scrollbar CSS in webpages (e.g. scrollbar-face-color)

v 1.2
---------
new: modern scroll can be displayed in fullscreen mode only
new: enhanced possibilities to adjust the interface (colors, transparency, border)
fix: area next to scroll bars isn't clickable (thx Aleksey for reporting)
fix: background bars show up although they are disabled (thx laurenbacall for reporting)

v 1.1
---------
new: top- and bottommost part of the background bar can be used to scroll to top / bottom
new: scroll bars can be attached to the opposite side of the screen
new: optional animation of bar during scrolling by mouse wheel / keyboard
new: contextmenu entry only shows up if you right-click the modern scroll interface (adjustable)
new: scroll button width and height adjustable
fix: scrollbar position not updated, when superbar is dragged to top left corner (thx Daniel for reporting)
fix: scrollbars don't have a border on some websites (e.g. iphoneforums.net)
fix: options page doesn't show any text if no supported language is chosen in Opera (thx Piotr for reporting)

v 1.0
---------
Initial release